{
    "id": "96653e6368e442ec99a62a42034273c4",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I asked her …………………………… she could help me.",
            "description": "Either if or whether can be used to introduce an indirect yes/no question.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d7ebedba2500444cba70ded42684caad"
        },
        {
            "question": "We waited ………………………………. he turned up.",
            "description": "Until shows time up to shows distance.",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "up to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ee9faa7cde884fb99b1e624f9f628fe6"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. I had invited a lot of people, no one turned up.",
            "description": "We use though to connect two contrasting ideas. As shows the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "Even as"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4e10f65ba814477ca1585dc07f544a03"
        },
        {
            "question": "I was delighted to hear …………………………… he was safe.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "that",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a2cca2b5487341c5a12062484762cc73"
        },
        {
            "question": "How would people live ……………………………… there was no electricity?",
            "description": "If indicates a condition.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "whether",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b9edb324f23b4d4189f70214025e3df4"
        },
        {
            "question": "I invited them ……………………………….. they didn’t come.",
            "description": "We use but to connect two clauses of equal rank expressing contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "but",
                "though",
                "since"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "94f00d3700144668b29876feb2da8ae6"
        },
        {
            "question": "You must work …………………………….. starve.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "or",
                "and",
                "nor"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b37df551cc5e460bbdf7c0be5eaf89e6"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is …………………………… rich nor influential.",
            "description": "The correct expression is neither/nor.",
            "answers": [
                "either",
                "neither",
                "not"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7ec1bbd31d844a44a6ae4c8fe1710db1"
        },
        {
            "question": "You are not better ……………………………. he is.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "than",
                "then"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3229d9c6124644008ad6441a9bb19cf1"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………. she has a good job, she does not have to depend on her parents.",
            "description": "Now that is similar to as.",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "Now that",
                "As"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "85e3539329114f7c98e1ff7243887d8a"
        },
        {
            "question": "You should mend your ways ………………………….. you want to get into trouble.",
            "description": "Unless means if...not. We can also write: You should mend your ways if you do not want to get into trouble.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "unless",
                "whether"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "98194712961743229bf818598570f2bb"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was ………………………….. a pleasant morning that I went for a walk.",
            "description": "Use such before adjective + noun use so before an adjective. ",
            "answers": [
                "such",
                "so",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "adcfc6cc867141709728b5ef680277e4"
        }
    ]
}